<ProductRequirementsDocument>
    <ProductName>Model/Data Card Web App</ProductName>
    <Version>MVP v2</Version>
    <Owner>Aether Team</Owner>
    <Date>2025-06-17</Date>

    <Overview>
        This web application allows users to upload, view, and edit model and data cards in JSON format. 
        The MVP has been developed and is functional, but requires enhancements to improve usability, 
        collaboration, and integration with GitHub.
    </Overview>

    <KeyFeaturesAndRequirements>
        <AuthenticationAuthorization>
            <Requirement>Use GitHub OAuth for user login.</Requirement>
            <Requirement>Restrict access to user-specific branches and cards.</Requirement>
        </AuthenticationAuthorization>

        <BranchManagement>
            <Requirement>Automatically create a new GitHub branch when a new card is uploaded.</Requirement>
            <Requirement>Allow users to view the main branch (default schema).</Requirement>
            <Requirement>Allow users to view their own branches only (no access to others’ branches).</Requirement>
            <Requirement>Branches selectable via dropdown menu.</Requirement>
            <Requirement>One branch per card; users can create multiple branches.</Requirement>
        </BranchManagement>

        <IssueLinking>
            <Requirement>Automatically create a new GitHub issue alongside the branch when a card is uploaded, and link the issue and branch to the uploading user.</Requirement>
            <Requirement>Provide a button to redirect to linked GitHub issue for each card.</Requirement>
        </IssueLinking>

        <CardManagement>
            <Requirement>Cards must be in JSON format.</Requirement>
            <Requirement>JSON cards can be viewed in a read-only treeview.</Requirement>
            <Requirement>JSON cards can be edited in a treeview editor (keys and values only).</Requirement>
            <Requirement>Users cannot modify the JSON hierarchy in the editor.</Requirement>
            <Requirement>To change the hierarchy, users must download the JSON, edit it externally, and re-upload the modified file.</Requirement>
        </CardManagement>
    </KeyFeaturesAndRequirements>

    <FunctionalRequirements>
        <Feature>
            <Name>GitHub Login</Name>
            <Description>OAuth-based login using GitHub API</Description>
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
            <Name>Upload Card</Name>
            <Description>Upload JSON file, auto-create branch and issue</Description>
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
            <Name>View Cards</Name>
            <Description>Treeview (read-only) and editable view</Description>
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
            <Name>Edit Cards</Name>
            <Description>Modify keys/values only</Description>
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
            <Name>Branch Dropdown</Name>
            <Description>Select from main or user-specific branches</Description>
        </Feature>
        <Feature>
            <Name>Download/Upload</Name>
            <Description>Download JSON for external editing and re-upload</Description>
        </Feature>
    </FunctionalRequirements>

    <NonFunctionalRequirements>
        <Requirement>Security: OAuth tokens must be securely stored and managed.</Requirement>
        <Requirement>Performance: JSON rendering and editing should be responsive for files up to 1MB.</Requirement>
        <Requirement>Scalability: Support for multiple users and concurrent sessions.</Requirement>
        <Requirement>Browser Compatibility: Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Edge.</Requirement>
    </NonFunctionalRequirements>
</ProductRequirementsDocument>


